<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beaver Ambassadors</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Beaver Ambassadors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Beaver Ambassadors</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>External Resources</title>
      <link>/courses/example/_index2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/courses/example/_index2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/topic/outreach-education&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NOAA (National Oceanic &amp;amp; Atmospheric Administration)&lt;/a&gt; is a leading federal environmental organization. NOAA has helped many other organizations, including zoos, aquariums and local jurisdictions, form educational material along with many lessons NOAA has developed in-house. Because NOAA is national they cover topics from Alaska to Hawaii to the Gulf of Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery Days</title>
      <link>/talk/tryon_beaver_activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/tryon_beaver_activity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOR A SPECIAL LAST SATURDAY TREAT, WANDER INTO ONE OF OUR CLASSROOM DISCOVERY DAYS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually reserved for more formal programs like camp and field trips, our nature classroom opens its doors on the last Saturday of every month with fun and educational hands-on activities for visitors of all ages.  This open-house style program has a ‘come and go as you please’ format, so feel free to drop by anytime during the hours listed above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jcwc.org/beavers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.jcwc.org/beavers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music in the Park</title>
      <link>/talk/music_in_the_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/music_in_the_park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is info for the Journey cover band performing this Thursday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portland based Journey tribute, “Girl Can’t Help It,” will have you Captured from Arrival to Departure, staying true to the original recordings with lead singer Miaya Shambry’s gritty powerhouse vocals, Dan Johnson slayin’ the guitar solos, Natasha Flynn’s timeless piano/synth hooks, Dianna Hnatiw driving deep on drums, and April Krubel bringin’ it, backing up the signature three part female harmonies that make this band’s unique take on old Journey favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beavers Help Salmon</title>
      <link>/post/beavers-help-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/beavers-help-salmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beavers and fish get along splendidly! They&amp;rsquo;ve evolved together, right here in the Pacific Northwest, for thousands of years. Beaver dams &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; prevent fish passage. Unlike human-made dams, fish can get around beaver dams in a variety of ways. People who generated the myth that beavers are bad for fish were likely trying to find ways to justify exploiting beaver pelts and/or falsely blaming decreased fish populations on beavers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of published, peer-reviewed science articles about relationships between beavers and salmon show beavers provide habitat for salmon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are a young salmon. It takes you about a year to get to the ocean. In that time you move from the place you were born constantly going downstream. You need lots of food and protection on your journey. You find some bugs (called macroinvertebrates) in the stream, but it&amp;rsquo;s tough to hang out in the current and the bugs tend to be in shallower areas - easy to get eaten by an osprey! Then you come across a beaver dam! The current slows, food is abundant AND easy to reach and there are plenty of sticks and logs to hide under! What a perfect place to hang out and bulk up for the rest of the journey downstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you&amp;rsquo;ve successfully navigated the great Pacific Ocean and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to return to Oregon&amp;rsquo;s rivers to reproduce. The current on the Columbia and Willamette is swift! You have to go through countless fish ladders because of all the dams people built (maybe you&amp;rsquo;re shot out of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mentalfloss.com/article/597138/fish-tube-how-salmon-cannon-works&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;fish cannon&lt;/a&gt;). You&amp;rsquo;re one of the lucky ones and you make it to a side stream off the Tualatin River, and lo! A beaver dam. It is spring and the waters are running over the dam, so you simply &lt;em&gt;SWIM UP&lt;/em&gt; and voila! You can take a nice, deserved break! The flow has slowed, the pond is huge, and there is &lt;strong&gt;plenty&lt;/strong&gt; of refuge to hide from predators - bears, owls, eagles. You hang out for a few days, regain your strength and head on to the headwaters where you&amp;rsquo;ll drop eggs in areas known as &lt;em&gt;redds&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of years ago, salmon would have encountered &lt;strong&gt;dozens&lt;/strong&gt; of beavers dams, each one more welcome than the last. It is entirely likely the decrease in salmon populations is affected by the decrease of beavers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t take my word for it&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beaverinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Do-Beaver-Dams-Impede-the-Movement-of-Trout-Lokteff-Roper-Wheaton-Transactions-American-Fisheries-Society-2013-2-2-2.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;US Forest Service biologists and watershed scientists&lt;/a&gt; have determined beavers &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; impede native fish passage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beaverinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/NMFS-ORCohoRecoveryPlan2016.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Beavers are mentioned &lt;strong&gt;232&lt;/strong&gt; times!&lt;/a&gt; in the Official Coho Recovery Plans written by NOAA Fisheries. I particularly like how the authors point out the importance of habitat complexity and provide examples of how habitats become complex including, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Beaver provide considerable help in providing this connection and in maintaining proper watershed functioning in Oregon coast streams.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Authors go on to include strategies to improve habitat, and the second strategy is: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Ensure long-term ecosystem functions and high quality habitat by reducing habitat-related threats and encouraging formation of beaver dams and beaver dam analogues.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;link...&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Beavers benefit threatened populations of Steelhead&lt;/a&gt; and this relationship was shown right here in Oregon! One of the greatest beaver models ever made was published in this scientific paper (it is less complex than it looks, just follow the arrows and see all the + signs!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/beaver_fish.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beaver_fish&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don&amp;rsquo;t take my word for it&amp;hellip;check out these links! Better yet, go play in a stream and pretend you&amp;rsquo;re a salmon! (don&amp;rsquo;t swim in a beaver pond though&amp;hellip;those are for wildlife only :))&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Beavers</title>
      <link>/talk/meet_the_beavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/meet_the_beavers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come out to Meet the Beavers on Tuesday nights throughout the summer of 2019! At Mary S. Young Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Beaver Ambassadors project began at Mary S. Young Park in West Linn because of the incredible accessibility people have to view, experience, and understand beavers and their activity. Beavers built a home where a cement trail intersects their pond! They come out at almost the same time every day – 8pm. You can go see them on your own. However, the Beaver Ambassadors will be on location Tuesday nights throughout the summer (unless noted otherwise). We want the community to meet the beavers! We can learn from so much from this amazing species. For those community members who have found the trail conditions challenging or the loss of trees disheartening I encourage you to come out to meet us! We’ve been working to find a balance, but managing this species brings unique challenges. We love to hold dialogues with anyone who shows interest, we’re open to suggestions, and we love collaborative solutions! Plus, we’ll probably see a whole lot more. Beavers create homes for all sorts of other plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &amp;amp; Where: Meet the Beavers at Mary S. Young Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When: Last one of the summer! August 20th, 8pm-9:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who: Anyone who enjoys nature! I’m a dog lover, but please leave your canine at home. This will make for better wildlife interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why: Have you seen a beaver before? If not, this is a perfect opportunity. If you have we’d love to have you share your experience and enjoy another with us!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Projects</title>
      <link>/project/other-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/other-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a list of other projects Beaver Ambassadors have pursued or are continuing to complete. Eventually, each project will have its own page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biodiversity surveys at Willamette Wetlands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Development of the Beaver Ambassadors outreach booth

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation of &amp;ldquo;Pin the Beaver in the Keystone&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mary S. Young Park beaver habitat management considerations

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biodiversity surveys in Mary S. Young Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foot bridge hydraulic study at Robinwood Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beaver zines!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cattails.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cattails&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/bb2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bb2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/ptbitk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ptbitk&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/willow_branch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;willow_branch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/newt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;newt&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cleaveland.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cleaveland&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beaver impacts on forest canopy community structure</title>
      <link>/project/msy-tree-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/msy-tree-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From 2017 to 2018 we sampled 465 large (greater than 5 meters tall) trees and stumps created by beaver activity. The goal was to determine how the forest canopy community might shift as a result of beaver activity. We took tree species and location in Mary S. Young Park in West Linn along Heron Creek:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/MSY_Heron_Creek.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MSY_heron_creek&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all records accumulated, 31% were stumps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/MSY_tree_all_records.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MSY_tree_all_records&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More statistical analysis should be completed, but results appear to show Oregon White Oak (&lt;em&gt;Quercus garryana&lt;/em&gt;) thrives in this area:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/MSY_tree_sample_species.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MSY_tree_sample_species&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oregon White Oaks have the ability to flourish in floodplains where Doug Fir fail to survive root inundation. Ash, maple, and cottonwood can flourish in floodplains as well, but these species are preferred food source for Oregon beavers. Could it be that beavers promote Oregon White Oak habitat in riparian areas? Literature fails to adequately address this question. Oregon White Oak habitat is among the most degraded in the nation with only 2% remaining from the range prior to European occupation. Agricultural development and loss of native communities are frequently cited as the major drivers behind the loss of white oak ecosystems. This work suggests beavers played a role in these dynamics as well. However, much more work needs to be done to prove this hypothesis! MSY is but one small region, and more sites need to be assessed to help determine a relationship. In the mean time, Parks &amp;amp; Rec management will use this finding to continue to promote white oak growth. Oaks are protected by beaver herbivory, and water levels are encouraged to increase within the forest to help choke out conifers. We’ll keep an eye on this site to further assess changes related to beaver activity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Update</title>
      <link>/post/website_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website_update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-new-look-at-ba&#34;&gt;Welcome to the new look at BA!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-have-more-options&#34;&gt;We have more options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.pdx.edu/~scm6/westlinn_leaflet.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Better linking&lt;/a&gt; to cool apps we&amp;rsquo;ve made for the community&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can more easily manipulate text &lt;code&gt;like highlighting&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-advanced-users-perhaps-in-r-https-sourcethemes-com-academic-docs-managing-content-create-a-blog-post&#34;&gt;For advanced users &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-a-blog-post&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;perhaps in R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can add snippets of code you could add to your project, or help you start your own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;leaflet() pipe
  color = blue
  addMarkers = etc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inserting-pictures&#34;&gt;Inserting pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/spirea_bee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;spirea_bee&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more capabilities in terms of adding albums and linking to other cool pictures, but for now here is a picture of a bumble bee on spirea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-tuned&#34;&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example preprint / working paper</title>
      <link>/publication/preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/preprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
   Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beaver Ambassador Interactive West Linn Map</title>
      <link>/project/ba_leaflet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ba_leaflet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example journal article</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>/publication/conference-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/conference-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
