<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Beaver Ambassadors</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Beaver Ambassadors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Beaver Ambassadors</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beavers Help Salmon</title>
      <link>/post/beavers-help-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/beavers-help-salmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beavers and fish get along splendidly! They&amp;rsquo;ve evolved together, right here in the Pacific Northwest, for thousands of years. Beaver dams &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; prevent fish passage. Unlike human-made dams, fish can get around beaver dams in a variety of ways. People who generated the myth that beavers are bad for fish were likely trying to find ways to justify exploiting beaver pelts and/or falsely blaming decreased fish populations on beavers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of published, peer-reviewed science articles about relationships between beavers and salmon show beavers provide habitat for salmon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are a young salmon. It takes you about a year to get to the ocean. In that time you move from the place you were born constantly going downstream. You need lots of food and protection on your journey. You find some bugs (called macroinvertebrates) in the stream, but it&amp;rsquo;s tough to hang out in the current and the bugs tend to be in shallower areas - easy to get eaten by an osprey! Then you come across a beaver dam! The current slows, food is abundant AND easy to reach and there are plenty of sticks and logs to hide under! What a perfect place to hang out and bulk up for the rest of the journey downstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you&amp;rsquo;ve successfully navigated the great Pacific Ocean and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to return to Oregon&amp;rsquo;s rivers to reproduce. The current on the Columbia and Willamette is swift! You have to go through countless fish ladders because of all the dams people built (maybe you&amp;rsquo;re shot out of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mentalfloss.com/article/597138/fish-tube-how-salmon-cannon-works&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;fish cannon&lt;/a&gt;). You&amp;rsquo;re one of the lucky ones and you make it to a side stream off the Tualatin River, and lo! A beaver dam. It is spring and the waters are running over the dam, so you simply &lt;em&gt;SWIM UP&lt;/em&gt; and voila! You can take a nice, deserved break! The flow has slowed, the pond is huge, and there is &lt;strong&gt;plenty&lt;/strong&gt; of refuge to hide from predators - bears, owls, eagles. You hang out for a few days, regain your strength and head on to the headwaters where you&amp;rsquo;ll drop eggs in areas known as &lt;em&gt;redds&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of years ago, salmon would have encountered &lt;strong&gt;dozens&lt;/strong&gt; of beavers dams, each one more welcome than the last. It is entirely likely the decrease in salmon populations is affected by the decrease of beavers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t take my word for it&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beaverinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Do-Beaver-Dams-Impede-the-Movement-of-Trout-Lokteff-Roper-Wheaton-Transactions-American-Fisheries-Society-2013-2-2-2.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;US Forest Service biologists and watershed scientists&lt;/a&gt; have determined beavers &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; impede native fish passage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beaverinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/NMFS-ORCohoRecoveryPlan2016.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Beavers are mentioned &lt;strong&gt;232&lt;/strong&gt; times!&lt;/a&gt; in the Official Coho Recovery Plans written by NOAA Fisheries. I particularly like how the authors point out the importance of habitat complexity and provide examples of how habitats become complex including, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Beaver provide considerable help in providing this connection and in maintaining proper watershed functioning in Oregon coast streams.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Authors go on to include strategies to improve habitat, and the second strategy is: &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Ensure long-term ecosystem functions and high quality habitat by reducing habitat-related threats and encouraging formation of beaver dams and beaver dam analogues.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;link...&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Beavers benefit threatened populations of Steelhead&lt;/a&gt; and this relationship was shown right here in Oregon! One of the greatest beaver models ever made was published in this scientific paper (it is less complex than it looks, just follow the arrows and see all the + signs!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/beaver_fish.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beaver_fish&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don&amp;rsquo;t take my word for it&amp;hellip;check out these links! Better yet, go play in a stream and pretend you&amp;rsquo;re a salmon! (don&amp;rsquo;t swim in a beaver pond though&amp;hellip;those are for wildlife only :))&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Update</title>
      <link>/post/website_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website_update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-the-new-look-at-ba&#34;&gt;Welcome to the new look at BA!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-have-more-options&#34;&gt;We have more options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://web.pdx.edu/~scm6/westlinn_leaflet.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Better linking&lt;/a&gt; to cool apps we&amp;rsquo;ve made for the community&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can more easily manipulate text &lt;code&gt;like highlighting&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-advanced-users-perhaps-in-r-https-sourcethemes-com-academic-docs-managing-content-create-a-blog-post&#34;&gt;For advanced users &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-a-blog-post&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;perhaps in R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can add snippets of code you could add to your project, or help you start your own!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;leaflet() pipe
  color = blue
  addMarkers = etc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inserting-pictures&#34;&gt;Inserting pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/spirea_bee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;spirea_bee&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more capabilities in terms of adding albums and linking to other cool pictures, but for now here is a picture of a bumble bee on spirea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-tuned&#34;&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
