<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>beavers on Beaver Ambassadors</title>
    <link>/tags/beavers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in beavers on Beaver Ambassadors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Beaver Ambassadors</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/beavers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Beavers</title>
      <link>/talk/meet_the_beavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/meet_the_beavers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come out to Meet the Beavers on Tuesday nights throughout the summer of 2019! At Mary S. Young Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Beaver Ambassadors project began at Mary S. Young Park in West Linn because of the incredible accessibility people have to view, experience, and understand beavers and their activity. Beavers built a home where a cement trail intersects their pond! They come out at almost the same time every day – 8pm. You can go see them on your own. However, the Beaver Ambassadors will be on location Tuesday nights throughout the summer (unless noted otherwise). We want the community to meet the beavers! We can learn from so much from this amazing species. For those community members who have found the trail conditions challenging or the loss of trees disheartening I encourage you to come out to meet us! We’ve been working to find a balance, but managing this species brings unique challenges. We love to hold dialogues with anyone who shows interest, we’re open to suggestions, and we love collaborative solutions! Plus, we’ll probably see a whole lot more. Beavers create homes for all sorts of other plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &amp;amp; Where: Meet the Beavers at Mary S. Young Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When: Last one of the summer! August 20th, 8pm-9:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who: Anyone who enjoys nature! I’m a dog lover, but please leave your canine at home. This will make for better wildlife interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why: Have you seen a beaver before? If not, this is a perfect opportunity. If you have we’d love to have you share your experience and enjoy another with us!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Beavers</title>
      <link>/events/meet_the_beavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/meet_the_beavers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come out to Meet the Beavers on Tuesday nights throughout the summer of 2019! At Mary S. Young Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Beaver Ambassadors project began at Mary S. Young Park in West Linn because of the incredible accessibility people have to view, experience, and understand beavers and their activity. Beavers built a home where a cement trail intersects their pond! They come out at almost the same time every day – 8pm. You can go see them on your own. However, the Beaver Ambassadors will be on location Tuesday nights throughout the summer (unless noted otherwise). We want the community to meet the beavers! We can learn from so much from this amazing species. For those community members who have found the trail conditions challenging or the loss of trees disheartening I encourage you to come out to meet us! We’ve been working to find a balance, but managing this species brings unique challenges. We love to hold dialogues with anyone who shows interest, we’re open to suggestions, and we love collaborative solutions! Plus, we’ll probably see a whole lot more. Beavers create homes for all sorts of other plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &amp;amp; Where: Meet the Beavers at Mary S. Young Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When: Last meeting of the summer! August 20th. 8pm-9:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who: Anyone who enjoys nature! I’m a dog lover, but please leave your canine at home. This will make for better wildlife interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why: Have you seen a beaver before? If not, this is a perfect opportunity. If you have we’d love to have you share your experience and enjoy another with us!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beaver impacts on forest canopy community structure</title>
      <link>/project/msy-tree-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/msy-tree-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From 2017 to 2018 we sampled 465 large (greater than 5 meters tall) trees and stumps created by beaver activity. The goal was to determine how the forest canopy community might shift as a result of beaver activity. We took tree species and location in Mary S. Young Park in West Linn along Heron Creek:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/MSY_Heron_Creek.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MSY_heron_creek&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all records accumulated, 31% were stumps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/MSY_tree_all_records.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MSY_tree_all_records&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More statistical analysis should be completed, but results appear to show Oregon White Oak (&lt;em&gt;Quercus garryana&lt;/em&gt;) thrives in this area:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/MSY_tree_sample_species.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MSY_tree_sample_species&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oregon White Oaks have the ability to flourish in floodplains where Doug Fir fail to survive root inundation. Ash, maple, and cottonwood can flourish in floodplains as well, but these species are preferred food source for Oregon beavers. Could it be that beavers promote Oregon White Oak habitat in riparian areas? Literature fails to adequately address this question. Oregon White Oak habitat is among the most degraded in the nation with only 2% remaining from the range prior to European occupation. Agricultural development and loss of native communities are frequently cited as the major drivers behind the loss of white oak ecosystems. This work suggests beavers played a role in these dynamics as well. However, much more work needs to be done to prove this hypothesis! MSY is but one small region, and more sites need to be assessed to help determine a relationship. In the mean time, Parks &amp;amp; Rec management will use this finding to continue to promote white oak growth. Oaks are protected by beaver herbivory, and water levels are encouraged to increase within the forest to help choke out conifers. We’ll keep an eye on this site to further assess changes related to beaver activity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
