<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks on Beaver Ambassadors</title>
    <link>/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks on Beaver Ambassadors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Beaver Ambassadors</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery Days</title>
      <link>/talk/tryon_beaver_activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/tryon_beaver_activity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;FOR A SPECIAL LAST SATURDAY TREAT, WANDER INTO ONE OF OUR CLASSROOM DISCOVERY DAYS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually reserved for more formal programs like camp and field trips, our nature classroom opens its doors on the last Saturday of every month with fun and educational hands-on activities for visitors of all ages.  This open-house style program has a ‘come and go as you please’ format, so feel free to drop by anytime during the hours listed above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source:: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jcwc.org/beavers/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.jcwc.org/beavers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music in the Park</title>
      <link>/talk/music_in_the_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/music_in_the_park/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is info for the Journey cover band performing this Thursday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portland based Journey tribute, “Girl Can’t Help It,” will have you Captured from Arrival to Departure, staying true to the original recordings with lead singer Miaya Shambry’s gritty powerhouse vocals, Dan Johnson slayin’ the guitar solos, Natasha Flynn’s timeless piano/synth hooks, Dianna Hnatiw driving deep on drums, and April Krubel bringin’ it, backing up the signature three part female harmonies that make this band’s unique take on old Journey favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the Beavers</title>
      <link>/talk/meet_the_beavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/meet_the_beavers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come out to Meet the Beavers on Tuesday nights throughout the summer of 2019! At Mary S. Young Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Beaver Ambassadors project began at Mary S. Young Park in West Linn because of the incredible accessibility people have to view, experience, and understand beavers and their activity. Beavers built a home where a cement trail intersects their pond! They come out at almost the same time every day – 8pm. You can go see them on your own. However, the Beaver Ambassadors will be on location Tuesday nights throughout the summer (unless noted otherwise). We want the community to meet the beavers! We can learn from so much from this amazing species. For those community members who have found the trail conditions challenging or the loss of trees disheartening I encourage you to come out to meet us! We’ve been working to find a balance, but managing this species brings unique challenges. We love to hold dialogues with anyone who shows interest, we’re open to suggestions, and we love collaborative solutions! Plus, we’ll probably see a whole lot more. Beavers create homes for all sorts of other plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &amp;amp; Where: Meet the Beavers at Mary S. Young Park&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When: Last one of the summer! August 20th, 8pm-9:30pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who: Anyone who enjoys nature! I’m a dog lover, but please leave your canine at home. This will make for better wildlife interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why: Have you seen a beaver before? If not, this is a perfect opportunity. If you have we’d love to have you share your experience and enjoy another with us!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
